His Highness is going up the mountain.
我家世子要上山
Please make way.
烦请让路
Won't you fight?
你不出手吗
The kid wishes to enjoy the view
这小子想看风景
and it has nothing to do with me.
干我何事
Why would I help him?
我干吗帮他
Your Highness,
世子
pardon me.
得罪了
Stop!
停手
Let him go up the mountain.
让他上山
You're in no position to give orders.
这还轮不到你来决定
It's Old Ancestor's order
老祖下令
that Xu Fengnian goes up Guniujiang.
让徐凤年登牯牛降
It's Old Ancestor's order?
老祖让他上去
How would I dare to lie to you?
这种事我怎敢骗二叔
Get out of the way.
让开
I'll lead the way.
我来带路
Go.
走
Here I am at last.
终于走到这个地方了
I, Xuanyuan Jingcheng,
轩辕敬城
ask to see you, Old Ancestor.
请老祖宗现身
Xuanyuan Dapan doesn't know that I'm going up the mountain, right?
轩辕大磐不知道我要上山吧
You made it up?
临时扯的谎
If he's dead,
如果轩辕大磐死了
no one will know it.
这谎就没人知道
What if he lives?
那他要是没死呢
Then everything's over.
那就什么都结束了
Who would care about a lie by then?
谁还会在乎一句谎话呢
Old man.
老头
Do you think she's got a better figure than me?
你觉得她身段好吗
She was raised well.
好生养
She's better than you.
比你强
So what?
有什么了不起
I'm still growing.
我还在长身体
It's fine.
没事
Xu Fengnian doesn't care about that.
徐凤年不在乎
I don't care how he feels.
谁要他在乎啊
It's been many years.
这么多年
I underestimated you.
倒是小瞧你了
You came because of your daughter?
是为你女儿来的
The hundred-year prestige of the Xuanyuan Family
轩辕家近百年威望
has been maintained by you.
全依仗老祖宗支撑
I, on behalf of the entire Xuanyuan Family,
我代表轩辕一族
thank you.
谢过老祖
Your daughter
你女儿
is the thank-you gift.
就是谢礼
But it's a wrong way.
然而这条路走错了
So what if it's wrong?
错又怎样
Here I challenge you.
轩辕敬城求战
Jingcheng,
敬城
have you read the resonance of the sky and the earth yet?
读书可曾读到天地共鸣
Do you know
你可知
which stage
到哪一步
is the Celestial Realm?
才算是天象境
Whether it's Celestial Realm or not,
是否天象
you'll see after the fight.
一试便知
I'd like to see
我倒要看看
if you can withstand over a hundred moves.
你能否熬过百招
What's happening?
怎么回事
Who is fighting with Old Ancestor?
老祖在跟谁动手
It has begun.
开始了
Who do you think will win?
你觉得谁能赢
I, of course, wish my father wins.
我当然希望我爹赢
But Xuanyuan Dapan is a Celestial Realm-stage master.
但轩辕大磐是天象境高手
He excels in all kinds of martial arts.
诸般武学 无不精通
To defeat him
要赢他
won't be easy.
谈何容易
I'd like
我愿只身
to shake Mount Kunlun alone.
撼昆仑
Is Celestial Realm really capable of changing the weather?
天象境真能凭心意改天象
It just happens that the thunder is rumbling.
只是凑巧撞上打雷天而已
If he could alter the weather,
要真能呼风唤雨
then there would be no draught or flood.
这天下就没旱灾涝灾了
I don't understand it.
反正我也不懂
It is what you say it is.
前辈说什么就是什么
Master Jingxuan is dead.
三爷死了
Xuanyuan Jingcheng killed him.
是轩辕敬城所杀
Nonsense.
胡说八道
Where is the nerd?
那书呆子人呢
He's on the snowfield.
上大雪坪了
Impossible.
不可能
Elder Li.
李前辈
How good is Xuanyuan Dapan?
这轩辕大磐到底什么水准
He lost to me when we had a sword match.
当年斗剑他输了
After that? I don't know.
这以后 我就不知道了
It looks he's better than before.
瞧着比当年长进了
What about her dad?
那她爹呢
Her dad?
她爹
From what I'm seeing here, he hasn't reached Celestial Realm yet.
山下瞧见 还不是天象境
He'll lose for certain, right?
那岂不是输定了
The realm stage isn't the only determinant.
境界未必能决定一切
Both Xuanyuan Dapan and Wang Xianzhi are at Celestial Realm,
轩辕大磐跟王仙芝都是天象境
but Wang can defeat him singlehanded.
人家一只手都能打赢他
What about you?
那您呢
The same. Singlehanded.
我一只手也行
This
这
is the best you can do, right?
就是你的极限了吧
The second one.
再起
The third one.
三起
Move air against the sea.
气行逆海
No matter who wins the match,
这一战 无论结果如何
you'll be a dead man for sure.
你都已是必死之身了
Please come with me,
还请老祖
Old Ancestor.
陪我同去
You?
就凭你
And your contrived Celestial Realm?
这投机取巧 堆出来的天象境
How come there are three tornados?
这怎么变三道了
There will soon be a result.
快有结果了
Live or die, it'll be decided soon.
生死胜败就在眼前了
It is him.
真的是他
He's going to win?
这是要赢了
Be careful, Old Ancestor.
老祖小心
He did it!
成了
This one attack of yours cost your life,
你不惜性命全力一击
but you still failed to hurt me.
又可曾伤得了我
You came, too.
你也来了
Good.
正好
After I end his life,
等杀了他之后
I'll fight you, God of Sword.
再与剑神一战
Since I couldn't kill you with the power of Celestial Realm,
既然天象境杀不了你
I'll have to
那我就
take another step up.
再上一层
The next stage of Celestial Realm
天象境再上一层 便是陆地神仙
Even Wang Xianzhi hasn't achieved it yet.
连王仙芝都没到这境界
How can you make it?
你怎上得了这一层
Old Ancestor,
老祖
have you heard of epiphyllum?
可曾听说过昙花
It decays as it blooms.
初开便败
Its magnificence lasts only an instant.
刹那芳华
This is
这便是
Immortal-on-Earth Realm.
陆地神仙之境
Immortal-on-Earth?
陆地神仙
Is it so easily achieved?
这境界说上就上吗
He's burning his own blood and vital energy
他这是用自身气血为薪柴
to ignite his heart flame
燃起心火
and mount the apex.
登临绝境
But like he said,
可就像他自己说的
it decays and it blooms.
初开便败
This is
他的性命
the end of his life.
也到了最后一刻
It's impossible.
这不可能
Even if you sacrifice your life,
就算是不惜性命
it's impossible
也不可能
for you to reach Immortal-on-Earth Realm.
真的达到陆地神仙之境啊
Doing good is as difficult as mountain-climbing.
从善如登
Still, Mount Kunlun is reachable.
虽难可达昆仑
You should really read carefully
老祖宗真的应该读一读
the books that you deem useless.
那些被你视为无用的书
If you don't comprehend the law of the universe,
若不能明了 世理天心
you'll never
你一辈子
achieve this stage in this life.
都不能登临此境
You aren't qualified to lecture me.
你也配和我讲大道理
Will you leave any last words to Mount Hui?
老祖还有什么遗言留给徽山
how much longer can you live?
又能活多久
If I dodge the best I can,
只要我全力躲闪
you won't be able to kill me.
你又怎么能杀我
In the end,
到头来
it'll be me who watches you
还是我亲眼看着你
die in regret.
不甘而亡
He'll just dodge?
打不过就躲
That's cheeky of him.
这也太不要脸了吧
That's called being realistic.
这是知进退
What would you do?
要是换作您呢
A sword-wielder never backs off.
用剑之人 只进不退
Seriously?
这也行
He still makes use of the sky.
还是用了天时
If he was an immortal on Earth,
若真是陆地神仙
he would be able to kill him with his own power.
靠自身就能杀他
He's amazing enough.
已经很了不起了
How much longer do you get to live?
你现在还能活多久啊
Dad.
爹
Wait, wait, wait.
等等 等等 等等
I can turn the authority over to Qingfeng.
我可以让青锋做家主
I swear
我可以发誓
that I'll never touch her.
永远不碰她
Please
请
ascend to the heavens, Old Ancestor.
老祖升天
Mount Hui
徽山
will be yours.
托付给你了
Dad.
爹
Old Ancestor has gone.
老祖离世
The family needs a leader.
家族不可一日无主
The heavy burden
如山重担
shall fall onto me.
只有我来承担
Disciples.
来人
Seize the daughter of the rebel.
将这谋逆者的女儿拿下
Wait.
等等
I, Xu Fengnian of North Liang,
北椋徐凤年
would like to lead Xuanyuan
愿借天意
following God's will.
主掌轩辕
Carry him away.
抬走
- Yes.
是
Ma'am.
夫人
Xuanyuan Dapan is dead.
轩辕大磐 死了
What about him?
他呢
How did he end up?
他什么结果
Master Jingcheng
大公子他
fought the old villain with his life,
他以一己之力搏杀老魔头
and eventually perished.
同归于尽了
You came to seek refugee?
你是来投靠的
Master Jingcheng said,
大公子说
if he dies in the battle,
他若战死
I'm to hand the sachet to you.
这锦囊 交于夫人
Your Highness,
世子
this is Mount Hui,
这是徽山
not North Liang.
不是北椋
Xuanyuan Jingcheng rebelled against the ancestor,
轩辕敬城 欺师灭祖
which is a heavy sin.
罪不容恕
How can his daughter command Mount Hui?
他的女儿怎能执掌徽山
Even if we put this aside,
就算撇开这不说
all family affairs
家族的诸般事宜
were handled by me and Jingxuan.
向来都是由我和老三共同打理
There's too much to attend to.
千头万绪
How does she cope?
她 如何接手
Even if she is given authority,
就算 她站上了高位
how many of us will obey?
族人 又有几人信服
You're in high status, Your Highness.
世子身份尊贵
I'm sure you'll handle everything well.
有您在 自然能压得住一切波澜
But how long will you stay in Mount Hui?
可您 又能守在徽山多久
He has a point.
他说得挺有道理啊
If I become the householder,
若我做了家主
I'd like to ally with North Liang.
也愿与北椋结为同盟
As for my niece,
至于我这侄女
you can have her.
可以赠予世子
You've got shameless uncles.
你家长辈都挺不要脸啊
Uncle Jingyi has an unruly personality.
我二叔心性桀骜
Now that Xuanyuan Dapan,
如今轩辕大磐已死
my dad and Uncle Jingxuan are all dead,
我爹和三叔也已离世
no one can hold his ambition in check now.
再也没人能压住他的野心
North Liang is far away from Mount Hui.
北椋与徽山相隔甚远
I bet he'll break loose of North Liang.
他一定会甩脱北椋控制
He may even stab you in the back.
甚至 会反身咬上一口
Do you dare
这样的盟友
to ally with someone like this?
你敢要吗
How are you better than me?
你又能好到哪里去啊
He's asking you a question.
他问你话呢
It's a tricky question.
这话不好回答啊
Why?
怎么说
If the girl says she's loyal to North Liang,
这丫头要是说忠于北椋
the Xuanyuan Family won't be happy.
轩辕家会不满
If she says she's loyal to the family,
要说一心为家族
then Xu Fengnian has no reason to help her.
那徐凤年干吗帮她
It'll be a wrong answer either way, right?
那不是选什么都错
Princess, you should think about it, too.
殿下也该想想
When the time comes,
有朝一日
what would you choose
故国和徐凤年
between your homeland and Xu Fengnian?
您会怎么选
Chess Master?
棋诏叔叔
A voice through air. No one else can hear it.
传音 别人听不见
You heard it, too?
您也听见了
It took him so much effort to find you,
好不容易找到你
would he leave you be?
曹长卿能放心吗
He's been with us along the way.
这一路他都在
I swear
我轩辕青锋发誓
that if I'm in charge of Xuanyuan,
若我执掌轩辕
I shall do all I can
必定竭尽所能
to reinvigorate our family,
振兴家族
making sure the Xuanyuan Family never falls again.
让轩辕家屹立不摇
Everybody can brag.
大话谁都会说
What actions will you take?
你凭什么做到
Once I'm the householder,
我为家主后
Wending Pavilion will be open to the entire family.
问鼎阁 将为全族开放
Even a retainer
即便是门客
gets to study inside of it.
也可入内研习武学
Reinvigorate the family?
振兴家族
I'm afraid the family would serve under certain people.
只怕 家族成了别人爪牙
Now that Xuanyuan Dapan is dead,
如今轩辕大磐已死
Mount Hui is out on a limb.
徽山孤立无援
The alliance with North Liang
此时依附北椋
will serve as the shelter for the Xuanyuan Family.
也可保轩辕家平安
But here I take a vow
但我于此发誓
that the Xuanyuan Family will never take orders from others.
轩辕 不会永远做别人棋子
- Before the next Celestial Realm rises, - It'd be perfect. Yeah.
等下一代天象境出现之前
the Xuanyuan Family
轩辕家 将会全力配合北椋行事
What if there's a new Celestial Realm?
那要是有了新的天象境呢
If there's one, we'll renegotiate the terms.
有了天象境 条件再谈
It's honest of you.
实在
You two can't decide the master
轩辕家主之位
of the Xuanyuan Family by talking.
可不是二位这么说话就能定的
Eventually,
到头来
it's decided by the will of our clansmen.
还是要看家族中人心中意愿
Everybody,
诸位
if our clan
若轩辕家
is under the control of such a young girl,
由这么一位黄毛丫头来做主
won't we be laughed at?
岂不成了天下人的笑话
Ask yourselves.
请各位扪心自问
Who's better suited to be the master?
谁更适合接掌轩辕
Isn't it obvious?
这还用选吗
Hierarchy is fundamental to a clan.
长幼尊卑 方为一族之本
Good point.
说得好
Hierarchy.
长幼尊卑
Qingfeng,
青锋啊
listen.
你且听听
This is the will of our clansmen!
这 才是人心所向
Speaking of hierarchy,
若要只说长幼尊卑
Master Jingcheng is the eldest lineal son
大公子才是嫡子长孙
and Miss Qingfeng should be the master
大小姐名正言顺
with the right reason.
正该是轩辕之主
Xuanyuan Jingyi died.
轩辕敬意身死
My Lady, take over the Xuanyuan Family.
恭请大小姐执掌轩辕
I didn't give that order.
不是我
Who else did that, then?
还能有谁
Your father is really something.
你爹不简单啊
The rain has stopped.
雨停了
The situation has changed.
天变了
Excuse me?
你刚才说什么
Didn't you hear me?
你没听清吗
Xuanyuan Jingcheng and Xuanyuan Dapan died together.
轩辕敬城和轩辕大磐同归于尽
Xuanyuan Qingfeng
轩辕青锋
will take over the Xuanyuan Family.
将要执掌轩辕
What do you think she'll do to you?
你觉得她会怎么对你
That's impossible.
不可能
I don't care if you believe that.
相不相信都可以
But you don't have too much time
可留给你做决定的时间
to make a decision.
不多了
Hold a decent funeral for Uncle Jingyi.
厚葬二叔
We will, My Lady.
大小姐放心
Take down Yuan Tingshan.
拿下袁庭山
Yes.
是
Search for him!
搜
- Yes.
是 是
Do you believe it now?
相信吗
Why did you come and inform me of it?
为什么来通知我
I want to help you.
帮你啊
Why?
为什么帮我
Xu Fengnian
徐凤年
has ruined your chance.
夺你机缘
Do you hate him?
恨不恨他
Shall we
不如
join hands to kill him?
一起杀他
I'm not a fool.
我不是傻子
If you want supreme martial arts,
你想要绝学
I can give you the books.
我能给你
If you want a bright future,
你想要前程
I can give it to you, too.
我也能给你
He's gone?
人走了
Go search for him!
找
You have no way out, anyway.
反正你也无路可走
Leave with me.
跟我过江吧
I have...
有
...a surprise
惊喜
for you.
给你
You may rise.
都起来吧
I'll keep my promise.
我说话算话
From this day on,
从今后
all clansmen of the Xuanyuan Family have access to Wending Pavilion
轩辕族人皆可进问鼎阁
to learn martial arts.
研习武学
Retainers making contributions are allowed in, too.
门客凡有功绩者亦可入内
Don't you fear that a genius will appear
你真不怕将来有天才横空出世
and take your place?
鸠占鹊巢
It's a special solution for this special period.
非常时期 非常手段
Now that I've made this decision,
我既然做了
I'm brave enough to face any consequences.
就敢面对任何结果
You indeed behave like a master.
有几分家主风范
Who are you, sir?
先生是
My name isn't worth mentioning.
贱名不足挂齿
I made a mistake and got my family involved.
在下当年犯错连累家人
Jingcheng saved my family.
是敬城兄救我全家性命
I must pay him back for that.
如此恩情 自当回报
My father left this to me?
我爹给我的
Yes.
是
One for me, too?
我也有
Your Highness, according to Jingcheng,
敬城兄说
after Xuanyuan Dapan died,
轩辕大磐死后
if you helped Miss Qingfeng,
若世子雪中送炭
I would give this to you.
这锦囊 便交于世子
It's foresighted of him.
神机妙算啊
Don't you open it?
你不打开
Your Highness, you haven't replied yet.
世子还未回答
What do you want from us?
您想要什么
Many people are around.
人多眼杂
Shall we have a private talk?
要不单独聊
Girl, you're enjoying the flowers?
小姑娘 赏花呀
It's sweet.
甜的
What?
什么
There's honey in the flower.
我说这花里有蜜
So, it tastes sweet.
尝起来是甜的
When I was gluttonous at a young age,
我小时候嘴馋
I often ate the petals.
就总摘着吃
Other girls
人家姑娘家
enjoy and love flowers.
都赏花 惜花
But you eat them.
你就想着吃
I live a hard life, so I love sweet things.
我命苦 就爱甜
It's indeed sweet.
是甜
My father loved reading.
我爹最爱读书
This is where he usually sat.
这是他常坐的位子
When he was tired,
他看书累了
he liked to look out of the window.
就总爱望着这边的窗外
Nothing special, I think.
好像也没什么呀
Yeah.
是啊
The window isn't near the river.
这窗外 不凭江
There's no scenery out there, either.
无山色
I don't know what he was looking at every day.
也不知道他天天看的是什么
I never understood
他心里想的
what he was thinking of.
我从未明白过
Fathers
做爹的
always behave like that.
都是这个样子的
They arrange everything,
什么都自己安排
take all the responsibility,
自己扛着
and never want to tell their children.
又不愿意说
You're right, I guess.
大概是这样吧
What's the letter about?
写的什么
Characters, preferences, and experiences
门客族人的性格喜好
of our clansmen and retainers.
生平际遇
He kept this to control them, I suppose.
大概是来把握人心的
I think it took him a long time.
大概准备了很久
If Xu Fengnian is too greedy,
徐凤年若贪念无穷
don't fight against him.
切勿相争
Take shelter
可投
from Mount Longhu.
龙虎山
On Tomb Sweeping Days,
从此清明
if your mother doesn't want to go to my tomb,
你娘若不愿上坟
don't force her.
不必勉强
When I can't spend my life with her,
不能相濡以沫
it's also my luck
便 江湖相忘
to set her free.
亦是幸事
Since you were born,
打你出生
I've buried jars of wine
爹在桂花树下
under the osmanthus tree.
埋下一坛酒
One jar for each year.
一年一坛
There have been 23 jars so far.
至此二十三坛矣
Privately, I call them
私下取名
Daughter's Wine.
女儿红
What do you think?
可好
Don't blame me for nagging.
莫怪爹唠叨
In the past,
这些年
I only said a few words to you
爹每年和你说话
every year.
不过五六句
I've got a lot to tell you,
心里攒了好些闲话
but I don't know how to start the conversation.
却不知从何说起
Qingfeng,
青锋
my biggest regret
爹最可惜的
is that I can't watch you get married.
是瞧不见你成家生子
If you get married,
若有将来
name your son Fuyao
孙子叫扶摇
and name your daughter Yasong.
孙女叫雅颂
All right?
可好
No matter whether they want to learn literature
他们想学文就学文
or martial arts, let them be.
想习武便习武
Life is short.
人生苦短
Living a simple life
糊糊涂涂过一辈子
will be a great thing.
就很好
It's better than my life.
总好过爹这样
I never got what I wanted
一生求而不得
and I made your mother hate me.
怨憎相会
In case you get annoyed,
怕你生厌
I'll say no more.
不再多说了
Wish you
祝
a good life
余岁安好
and a healthy body.
无病无灾
I understand now.
我明白了
Seen through the window,
从这窗外看过去
there's no scenery.
什么都没有
But you look farther on,
但一直往下去的方向
you'll see the house where my mother and I live.
就是我和我娘的院子
What message did he leave for you, Your Highness?
给世子留的什么
Well, your father...
你这个爹啊
Mount Hui has declined.
徽山没落
Your Highness, if you want our clan,
世子若想取而代之
please spare my daughter's life.
只求留小女一条性命
There're treasures and secret books in Xuanyuan Dapan's mansion.
轩辕大磐府内奇珍秘籍
They're all yours.
尽献世子
Xuanyuan Dapan lives on Snowfield Guniujiang.
大雪坪上便是轩辕大磐的住处
You can take away whatever you want.
世子可自便
I don't want the treasures
我不要徽山财宝
or secret martial arts of your family.
也不要轩辕绝学
So, you want me?
那就是要我
Qingniao, who's out of the room,
门外青鸟
is as beautiful as you.
论相貌不输于你
She has better martial arts than you.
武艺远在你之上
She isn't very talkative.
虽然话不多
But she's sensible and witty.
但是知情识趣
She's a talented and wise girl.
才智双绝
In my mansion, I've got six or seven maids
像这样的丫鬟
just like her.
小爷我府上还有六七个
Why do I want you?
我要你干吗
Your Highness,
那请问世子
what exactly do you want from my family?
究竟想从轩辕家得到什么
Wait a minute.
你等我一下
So sweet.
真甜
Have some more, then.
多吃点
Sweet.
甜
Qingniao.
青鸟啊
Would you like some?
来点儿
It's very good.
好东西
Sweet.
甜
What?
干吗
Some business.
有事
You're gathering honey?
您这是采蜜呢
It's very sweet.
挺甜的
Senior,
前辈
you're the God of Sword, after all.
您好歹是个剑神
Don't put everything in your mouth.
别什么东西都往嘴里塞
Would you like some?
来点不
Don't stand on ceremony. Here.
别客气 来点
She's my maid.
我家丫鬟
To be honest,
不瞒你说
she's the princess of West Chu.
西楚公主
Don't talk nonsense.
你别瞎说
When we want a favor from her,
你想要人家帮忙
we can't hide your identity.
你的身份瞒不住
Princess of West Chu?
亡国公主
How shall I help her?
怎么帮
In a couple of days,
这几日
she's going back to West Shu.
她就要回西蜀
It's a long trip.
千里路遥
The fastest and safest way
最快最安全的走法
is to travel by water.
就是走水路
Escorting her back home
把她安全送到
is the first favor I want from you.
就是要你帮的第一个忙
I can travel alone.
我自己能走
Cao Changqing has great martial arts.
曹长卿虽然武功高
But he doesn't take good care of people.
但终究不会照顾人
If you travel on their boat,
有他们家的船
you can be more relieved.
你路上安心些
Invincible Cao Changqing.
官子无敌曹长卿
You're warning me, Your Highness?
世子这是敲打我呢
Clever girl.
聪明人
We don't need to be very specific.
不用都说穿
You awed our clan with an umbrella,
世子执伞镇徽山
just for this girl around you?
就是为了身边人
It's so considerate of you.
够用心的
I have no other choice.
没办法
My girl still owes me some money.
我家丫头还欠我钱
She must be safe.
不能出事
Who owes you?
谁欠你钱了
Didn't I spend money raising you for so many years?
这么多年吃喝不花钱吗
Make a list, then.
那你列个明细
I'll pay you back when I have money.
我有钱还你
The interest should be included.
得算利息
No matter how much you want me to pay,
不管你怎么算
I'll pay it off.
我都认
Young Master of North Liang. Princess of West Chu.
北椋世子 西楚公主
Who could expect that?
这谁能想到
What?
想到什么
Nothing.
没什么
Your Highness, when you need the boat,
世子何时用船
just let me know.
开口便是
After I leave Mount Longhu,
等我下了龙虎山
she should leave, too.
就该走了
You're going to Mount Longhu?
你还要登龙虎山
What do you want? To get killed?
你是嫌自己命太长了吗
When someone wants to kill me,
真要杀我
he'll do it wherever I go.
绕着走也要杀的
It's a deal, then.
那就一言为定
What else do you want, Your Highness?
世子还有什么要求
I indeed want another favor
确实还有一件事
from your family.
也要轩辕家帮忙
I need your boats, too.
也是用船
For escorting someone?
又送人
No.
不
For picking up someone.
这次是接人
Who?
哪位
Some people from different places.
不止一人 不止一处
It'll be troublesome.
会比较麻烦
We do business in all waterways.
天下水路 皆有轩辕
No matter whom you want to pick up,
不管接谁
just tell me.
世子尽管开口
I can't tell you
时机到了
until the time has come to act.
才能告知
In case I give away your secret?
怕我泄密
I've prepared my plan
我准备的事
for such a long time
谋划太久
and too many people are involved.
牵涉太广
I have to keep it to myself only.
只能放在这里
I won't tell anyone
不到最后关头
until the last minute.
谁也不会告诉